{
  "reference_number": "11625",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We should not set any target."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No target."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Consult with business owners and those who are going to be effected by this. Keep the public informed is #1 priority."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No foreign NGO or government should have any say over what our government does unless it's non-binding and 100% paid for at\n their expense."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "scrap all of it"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The science behind this is politically motivated and the models are being constantly revised and changed as they fail to accurately\n\npredict the changes we are seeing in the climate. We need to understand the effect of Space Weather and the effect of the sun\nbeing at a solar minimum on the planet. The weather is changing on every planet in our solar system not just Earth. This is easily\n\nverifiable and noted by NASA and other space agencies around the world. So are we sure that it is the CO2 causing the climate to\nchange? Greenhouse effect is definitely real but is it really as bad as we are being made to believe? People don't want to accept that\n\nin order to get research grants you have to not go too far outside established theory. Who decides who gets the research grants?\nJust like Doctors promoted smoking or the Catholic Church refused to accept a heliocentric model scientists can and do get it wrong\n\nsometimes at a grand scale. When we look at the biggest polluters in the world they are not those being most targeted by climate\nchange law. This is because they are so called 'developing nations' such as China and India.Now USA totally withdrew from the Paris\nAccords. Although they have made commitments and are making some token gestures they continue to pollute on a scale that\n\ndwarfs NZ. Even if we were to purposefully pollute and emit carbon as much as we could we couldn't ever hope to match even a tiny\nportion of what they output. Right now our economy isn't doing well. 15% GST on basic food items, increasing fuel tax, ignoring our\n\nnatural gas reserves and other natural resources, and other taxes are making NZ an unproductive nation where people cannot/don't\nwant to open businesses. Poor people are hurting and even living in cars. Having to beg the government for assistance as there\n\naren't enough jobs for them to get a decent wage. We are not in any way big enough to be considered part of this problem where it is\nworth hurting our economy. We are not a rich nation. We are far poorer than other nations which are considered developing and falling\nfurther behind. We need to make sure our economy is strong otherwise our emissions certainly will drop if we enter into a Venezuela\n\ntype situation. For example if something like Mad Cow Disease broke out here think of what a position we would be in. This is not the\nonly scenario we should be considering. An Earthquake in Auckland which damaged the harbor bridge is another example of\n\nsomething that would cripple us economically. We absolutely must put our economy first before we start to consider global\ncommitments and virtue signaling. There's no point in being the #1 in reduced carbon emissions on the hollowed out shell of a\n\nnation."
    }
  ]
}
